Guide to the Paul Cooper papers, 1943-1995 MS 463
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Compositions (scores and recordings), 1943-1993
  - Subseries C: Recordings, 1963-1993
    - Sub-subseries 5: Vocal/Solo
      - Mirrors (1986), Sonanza of Stockholm, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 10/9/1986 (Box 25, Tape 33)
      - Mysterion (1988), M.S.U. Orchestra, Beverly Hay, soprano, John Baur, narrator, Don Freund, conductor, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 31)
      - Mysterion (1988), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 34)
      - Mysterion (1988), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 35)
      - Mysterion (1988), n.d. (Box 25, Tape 36)
      - Seventeen Haiku, Cimmaron Wind Quintet, Sumiyo Ender, soprano; Paul Page, Harp, Graduate students of the Shepherd School, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 37)
      - Seventeen Haiku (version for orchestra), Sumiyo Ender, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 2)
      - Seventeen Haiku (version for orchestra), Sumiyo Ender, soprano, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 3)
      - Silences (1973), Patti Spain, Pre-recorded (take 3), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 30)
      - Silences (1973), Albert Tipton, flute, Michael Rosenberg, oboe, Paul Ellison, doublebass, Anne Schnoebelen, harpsichord, Hamman Hall, Rice University, SYZYGY Retrospective Concert: Music of Paul Cooper, 11/30/1978 (Box 32, Tape 10)
      - Silences for Soprano, flute Alto flute, oboe English horn, harpsichord celesta, doublebass percussion; on poems of C.E.Cooper, Heritage Quartet, Helen Laird, soprano, Corbett Center of the Performing Arts, 2/1/1974 (Box 32, Tape 4)
      - Silences, pre-record tape, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 14)
      - Songs of Antigone, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 21)
      - Songs of Antigone, U.S.C. Contemporary Ensemble, Robert Wajciak, director, 11/3/1980 (Box 26, Tape 22)
      - Songs of Antigone (1979), n.d. (Box 27, Tape 11)
      - Songs of Antigone (1979), Poems of C.E.Cooper, Cambiata soloists: Isabelle Ganz, mezzo-soprano, Arthur Gottschalk, synthesizer, Ellsworth Milburn, conductor, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 1/28/1980 (Box 31, Tape 19)
      - Songs of Antigone (Poems of C.E.Cooper, Isabelle Ganz, mezzo-soprano, Joe David Bonner, flute and alto flute, Michael Rosenberg, oboe, Laura Witt, harp, Steven McMillan, violin, Wayne Crouse, viola, Steve Estes, violoncello, Paul Ellison, contrabass, Michael Moores, conductor, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 4)
      - Tomorrow's Songs, Caruth Auditorium, SMU, 9/15/1975 (Box 30, Tape 17)
      - Tomorrow's songs (1974), 11/6/1990 (Box 26, Tape 8)
      - Tomorrow's songs (1974), n.d. (Box 26, Tape 9)
      - Tomorrow's songs (1974) Five poems on a text by C.E.Cooper), Mary Jo Tynon, Soprano, Susanne Oldham, Alto flute, Robert Nisbett, Piano, Colorado State University, Dept of Music, Music Building, Concert Hall, A recital of Compositions by Paul Cooper, 4/7/1975 (Box 31, Tape 11)
    - Sub-subseries 6: Broadcast
      - "The Poets' Corner" by WGUC Radio, University of Cincinnati, Interview and reading of poetry by C.E.Cooper, Broadcast on WGUC, 8/4/1974 (Box 32, Tape 6)
      - Interview in Berlin with RIAS,, Carl Ebert and Wolfgang Geiseler, 5/24/1905 (Box 32, Tape 31)
      - Paul Cooper on WNIB, Chicago, 4/9/1988 (Box 25, Tape 9)
    - Sub-subseries 7: Lecture
      - "Franz Joseph and Friends" lecture, Philharmonia Orchestra, Choruses of the College-Conservatory, Elmer Thomas, conductor, Cincinnatti, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 18)
      - "Reflections on the the Human Spirit -- Spiritual Aspects of 20th Century Music" -- Best of Rice Lectures, 1990 (Box 26, Tape 4)
      - "Spiritual Aspects of 20th Century Music" Lecture, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 20)
      - 20th Century Class Project, 1963 (Box 33, Tape 12)
      - Lecture examples: "A personal creative process", n.d. (Box 25, Tape 10)
      - Provost Lecture by Paul Cooper, 10/22/1981 (Box 30, Tape 8)
      - Rice Composers' Seminar: "Music and Words", C.E. Cooper, Poet, 1/27/1982 (Box 32, Tape 5)
    - Sub-subseries 8: Unknown
      - "Just a passing phase", n.d. (Box 25, Tape 6)
      - [Composer's note: Work Unknown: Withhold?], n.d. (Box 26, Tape 17)
      - [no title] by Paul Cooper, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 6)
      - [Not legible], East Meets West, 10/17/1989 (Box 27, Tape 22)
      - 200 Animals (Cooper?), n.d. (Box 29, Tape 32)
      - Antigone, 3/31/1980 (Box 31, Tape 6)
      - blank tape, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 12)
      - Chamber Music Recital, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 34)
      - Christmas music, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 38)
      - Cooper, East Meets West, 10/17/1989 (Box 27, Tape 22)
      - Cooper: "Quodlibet", George Burt's 60th Birthday Gala, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 16)
      - Duncan, 2/19/1996 (Box 24, Tape 22)
      - Houston Composers Alliance, 11/1/1988 (Box 24, Tape 23)
      - Ian's songs, 6/2/1982 (Box 31, Tape 2)
      - Ian's songs, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 17)
      - Landschaft, New York Music Ensemble, LACMA-Bing Theatre, 11/7/1988 (Box 25, Tape 30)
      - Missa Brevis (Cooper?), USC Retro, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 13)
      - Music for a festive occasion, 10/6/1991 (Box 25, Tape 27)
      - No title, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 41)
      - No title, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 42)
      - No title, Stude Hall, Rice University, Syzygy concert, 11/19/1992 (Box 25, Tape 38)
      - no title, Electric Arts Duo, 10/3/1964 (Box 29, Tape 2)
      - No title, Chicago Symphony Orchestra - Reiner, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 24)
      - No title, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 12)
      - No title, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 18)
      - No title, [Note: "IB Norholm"], n.d. (Box 32, Tape 2)
      - Pierrot Project, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 30)
      - Pierrot Project III, "Die Wolken", "Sonnen-Ende", Da Capo Chamber Players, Lucy Shelton, soprano, Arnold Schoenberg Institute, 1/25/1989 (Box 25, Tape 29)
      - Rupp's inauguration, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 37)
      - Song from the Sacred Harp, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 22)
      - SYZYGY Concert, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 10/28/1981 (Box 32, Tape 8)
      - Tribute to Benny Goodman, Electric Arts Duo, Bowling Green OH, 7/3/1987 (Box 29, Tape 1)
      - Untitled, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 2)
      - Untitled, 1965 (Box 30, Tape 24)
      - untitled, n.d. (Box 31, Tape 3)
      - Winter Poems, Stockholm, premiere, n.d. (Box 24, Tape 28)
      - Winter Songs, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 5)
      - Winter Songs, (studio recording), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 30)
      - Works by Cooper and Saylor, Houston Symphony Orchestra, 11/20/1982 (Box 30, Tape 13)
      - Works by Duffay, Antheim, Cooper, and Br[illegible], Shepherd Symphony Orchestra and Choir, 10/4/1991 (Box 24, Tape 24)
      - Works by Lennon, Derr, and Cooper, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 1)
    - Sub-subseries 9: Other composers
      - Works by Schiedt, Cooper, Coneicao, Demessieux, Bates Recital Hall, 5/1985, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 18)
      - Bartok: Music for Strings, Percussion and celeste, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 19)
      - Baur: Canti II: Prisms, CCM Chamber Choir, CCM Philharmonic Orchestra, Elmer Thomas, Conducting, 4/27/1975 (Box 31, Tape 20)
      - Bradshaw, East Meets West, 10/17/1989 (Box 27, Tape 22)
      - Budd Udell: Judgement, The University Choir Chamber Orchestra, Budd Udell, conductor, Dept. of Music, University of Florida, 2/4/1978 (Box 31, Tape 25)
      - Cage: Perilous Night, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 32)
      - Canons d'amour (1981), n.d. (Box 26, Tape 40)
      - Carben: I Carus, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 32)
      - Chailley: Improvisation a Deux, Recording project, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 39)
      - Claudia (David's Wedding Music (15th Century Spanish), n.d. (Box 33, Tape 30)
      - Contemporary piano music not by Cooper, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 14)
      - Copland: Piano Variations, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 32)
      - Edwin Domb: Variants for Organ, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 11)
      - Electronic music by Davidovsky, Bassett, and Wilson, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 10)
      - Ellsworth Milburn: String Quintet (1969); Soli II for Flutes and double bass (1969), n.d. (Box 33, Tape 26)
      - Ena Memorial Service, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 12)
      - Finney: Three pieces for Strings, Woodwind, Percussion and Magnetic Tape, Commentary and music, 5/20/1963 (Box 32, Tape 13)
      - Finney: Violin Concerto No 2, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 29)
      - Finney: Violin Concerto No 2, Dallas Symphony Orchestra, Robt Gerle, Louis Lane, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 41)
      - Five works (composer unknown), Shenandoah Festival - A Shanandoah for Ives' Birthday, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 7)
      - Fourth Symphony by A.Melikov (in cyrillic), I.Rozhdestvensky, conductor, Moscow, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 3)
      - Fuchs: 12 Duette, op 60, Recording project, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 39)
      - George Burt: "Exit Music" for Twelve Players, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 22)
      - Gottschalk: "What are you doing?", George Burt's 60th Birthday Gala, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 16)
      - Halsey Stevens: Suite (1969), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Concert: "The 20th Century Violinist", 4/8/1981 (Box 33, Tape 8)
      - Handel-Halvorsen: Passacaglia, Recording project, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 39)
      - Ives: Unanswered Question, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 19)
      - Jones: "A Hocket for George", George Burt's 60th Birthday Gala, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 16)
      - Lavenda: "HBGB", George Burt's 60th Birthday Gala, n.d. (Box 26, Tape 16)
      - Lecture: "The music I like and why", Larry Livingston, Composers' seminar, 2/3/1982 (Box 30, Tape 9)
      - Lutoslawski: Symphony No 3, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 4)
      - McKinley: A Different Drummer, The New York New Music Ensemble, 11/5/1989 (Box 26, Tape 15)
      - Milburn: Scherzo, John Hendrickson, piano, Duncan Hall, Rice University, 2/18/1992 (Box 26, Tape 32)
      - Milburn: Spiritus Mundi (1974) for mezzo-soprano, five insturmentalist, and conductor (text by C.E.Cooper), n.d. (Box 31, Tape 33)
      - Milburn: String Quintet: Soli II, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 28)
      - Mozart: Magic Flute, Toscanini, 1937, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 20)
      - Mozart: Magic Flute, Toscanini, 1937, n.d. (Box 30, Tape 22)
      - Musgrave: Elegry for viola and cello, 1970, Peter Mark and Geoffrey Rutkowski, n.d. (Box 33, Tape 15)
      - Musgrave: Elegy for Viola and Cello, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 40)
      - Musgrave: Music for Horn and Piano, Tuckwell - Lee, 7/31/1969 (Box 33, Tape 16)
      - Musgrave: Narcissus, The New York New Music Ensemble, 11/5/1989 (Box 26, Tape 15)
      - New York Rock Ensemble, Yes, ELP, n.d. (Box 32, Tape 9)
      - Ochoa: Brass Quintet "Rice the Pleasure Pain", Paragon Brass Quintet, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 28)
      - Oleksandar Obradovic: Epitaph "H", n.d. (Box 30, Tape 14)
      - Paulina Stark: Concert (Part #2), n.d. (Box 30, Tape 19)
      - Philip Lindsay Master's Thesis: "In the Quiet Saffron Hour", Shepherd Sinfonia, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 1/29/1980 (Box 33, Tape 17)
      - Rachm No 3 (illegible), n.d. (Box 24, Tape 25)
      - Ravel: Scarbo, Bill Holmquest, piano, Wigmore Hall, 11/6/1970 (Box 27, Tape 13)
      - Requiem for organ and percussion, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 18)
      - Riegger: Concerto for Piano and Wind Quintet, Op.53, Marlboro, Vermont, Marlboro Music Festival, 8/13/1970 (Box 30, Tape 21)
      - Riley: Third String Quartet, Concord String Quartet, 1/23/1977 (Box 32, Tape 30)
      - Ross Lee Finney: Sonata No. 2 (1953), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Concert: "The 20th Century Violinist", 4/8/1981 (Box 33, Tape 8)
      - Ross Lee Finney: Sonata No2 for viola and piano, Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, 4/8/1981 (Box 31, Tape 18)
      - Samuel Jones: Elegy for String Orchestra, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 15)
      - Samuel Jones: Elegy for String Orchestra, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 16)
      - Samuel Jones: Let us now Praise, Houston Symphony Orchestra, Samuel Jones, conductor, n.d. (Box 25, Tape 16)
      - Schwanter: In Aeternum SIDE B, The New York New Music Ensemble, 11/5/1989 (Box 26, Tape 15)
      - Strandberg: Sea of Tranquility, n.d. (Box 27, Tape 39)
      - Stravinsky: Requiem Canticles (Columbia MS7386), n.d. (Box 32, Tape 11)
      - Vincent Persichetti: Infanta Marina, Op. 147 (1960), Wayne Crouse, viola, Mary Norris, piano, Hamman Hall, Rice University, Concert: "The 20th Century Violinist", 4/8/1981 (Box 33, Tape 8)
      - Wayne Barlow: Soundprints in concrete, n.d. (Box 29, Tape 25)
      - Works by Gabrieli, Saint-Saens, Daniel Pinkham, Rice Chorale, First Presbyterian Church, Houston, Texas, 11/28/1989 (Box 29, Tape 16)
      - Works by James Marshall, Alban Berg, Igor Stravinsky, Alan Houhaness, Voices of Change (Demo tape), n.d. (Box 29, Tape 26)